<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-19T20:53:07-05:00</updated><id>https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bolu’s corner</title><subtitle>I express my thought about my work and projects in data analytics, clinical informatics and healthcare.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 1: Introduction to GSoC and LibreHealth</title><link href="https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/fastpages/jupyter/2020/05/19/Week-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1: Introduction to GSoC and LibreHealth" /><published>2020-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/fastpages/jupyter/2020/05/19/Week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/fastpages/jupyter/2020/05/19/Week-1.html">&lt;!--
#################################################
### THIS FILE WAS AUTOGENERATED! DO NOT EDIT! ###
#################################################
# file to edit: _notebooks/2020-05-19-Week-1.ipynb
--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; id=&quot;notebook-container&quot;&gt;
        
    
    
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
    

&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Introduction&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;My name is Bolu Oluwalade. I recently, in May 2020, obtained my masters of science degree in Health informatics from IUPUI ,USA .#goJags Since 2018, I have contributed to various Health IT projects that leverage my knowledge and skills in data analysis and visualization, machine learning, statistical learning, healthcare interoperability standards and clinical decision support. Prior to that, I worked as a Clincal Laboratory Scientist in both the private and public hospitals in Nigeria. I also worked on various public health projects related to HIV/AIDs, Tuberculosis and malaria.
My proposal to ‘Create web components for FHIR resources’ was accepted for GSoC 2020. I will contribute to the development of the LibreHealth EHR, an open-source EHR maintained by LibreHealth
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;Project-Description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Project-Description&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;The HL7 has developed several standards of EHR interoperability such as the HL7 V2, V3, Reference Information Model (RIM), and the Clinical Document Architecture (CDA). These standards are widely used in EHR systems. Most recently, the HL7 has developed a new standard called the Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources (FHIR) based on the RESTful API. FHIR is built on a set of components called Resources, which combines the best features of the CDA, HL7 v2, and HL7 v3. A resource can be used to store and exchange healthcare data over an HTTP endpoint using GET/POST request. This makes data exchange seamless and lightweight compared to other standards. In this project, I will develop web components for FHIR resources using the Polymer Library. The Polymer Library can be used to create web components using HTML imports, HTML Template, Shadow DOM, and custom elements. These created web components can be used in numerous EHR systems. Also, the web components are integrated into the LibreHealthToolkit. This project is a continuation of the previous LibrehealthToolkit project from the previous GSoC. The figure below shows the architecture of a typical web component.
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/images/some_folder/your_image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://boluabraham.github.io/bolu-oluwalade/images/some_folder/your_image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>